PRAGATI VASHISHTHA

linkedin.com/in/pragati-vashishtha/ | github.com/pragati020194 | bloomardochsho.in/about-me/

vashishthapragati2@outlook.com | +91-9717380198 | live:vashishthapragati2

ABOUT ME

I am a meticulous Developer with around 5 years of total experience, holistic knowledge of Responsive & Cross-Browser Development, a firm believer in Mobile-First Approach and Optimizations. I am also experienced in communicating & coordinating with clients, managers, leads & manage team.

EDUCATION

- **BHARATI VIDYAPEETHS** INSTITUTE OF **COMPUTER APPLICATIONS AND** MANAGEMENT (BVICAM), DELHI Master in Computer Applications (M.C.A.) - (GGSIPU) May 2018 | Percentage: 76.30
- **BANASTHALI** VIDYAPITH, **RAJASTHAN**

Bachelor in Computer Applications (B.C.A.) - (Banasthali University) July 2015 | Percentage: 55.90

AGRA PUBLIC SCHOOL, AGRA XII - (C.B.S.E.) May 2012 | Percentage: 70.20

ST. FRANCI'S CONVENT SCHOOL, **AGRA**

X - (C.B.S.E.)

May 2010 | Percentage: 76.00

SKILLS

Front End Development Skills: HTML | CSS | JS | JS Library | JS Tools CSS Framework CSS Preprocessor | Responsive UI Cross Browser API Dev-Tools Node MongoDB

Other Skills:

ECMA Script | Version Control | MySQL | Heroku | WordPress | Unit Testing | Postman | Jenkins | Slack | Jira | Docker

EXPERIENCE

WALKINGTREE TECHNOLOGIES

CAISSE NATIONALE DE SECURITE SOCIALE (GOVT SECT) | SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | May 2023 - Present

CNSS manages the compulsory social security scheme for all private sector employees in Morocco. Congo & U.S clients require documents to get converted and viewed in soft copy therefore installing DynamsoftServiceSetup.msi for scanner & pdf-excel-image viewer in it. Technologies Used: • Node18 • Tailwind CSS3 • ReactJs17 • GitHub • ES6/7 • Figma • Rest API • Yarn/NPM • JEST • Postman • Jenkins • Slack • JIRA • micro-frontend

PROJECT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (IT SECT) | FRONTEND SUPERVISOR | Feb 2023 -May 2023

I restructured and optimized the UI and development of the project with best practices. Along with assigning and handling the task to the juniors. Review and merging the code on dev branch on git and deploying it. Technologies Used: • Material UI • NPM • ES6/7 • Rest API • webpack • ReactJs17 • JSX • Redux-Thunk • Postman • Jenkins • Git/GitHub • Redmine • Node16 • Responsive UI • Cross Browser

- QRITRIM (IT SECT) | SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | Jan 2023 Feb 2023 It enables you with Artificial Domain Intelligence where it converts track record data into meaningful insights that all business can trust in future. I handled the front end of the project. Technologies Used: • JSON • Bootstrap5 • ES6/7 • Rest API • Yarn/NPM • webpack • ReactJs17 • Material UI • Redux-Saga • Redash • Docker • MongoDB • JDK • Postman • Node16 • Responsive UI • Cross Browser
- PIRAMAL-iLMS (GOVT SECT) | SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | Dec 2022 Jan 2023 It is digitalization of Integrated Litigation Management System for Piramal using DIGIT which has reusable building blocks which e-Govt. foundation supports. Technologies Used: • DIGIT • JSX • Tailwind CSS3 • ES6/7 • Rest API • Yarn/NPM • webpack • Git/GitHub • Figma • Node14 • Responsive UI • Cross Browser

DEPRONTO INFOTECH

ICICI PRUDENTIAL LIFE INSURANCE COMPANY (BANKING SECT) | FRONT END DEVELOPER | Aug 2019 - Nov 2022

Dynamic, responsive, cross-browser & optimized website as per the client requirement which provides different types of savings & protection policies. They are created with coordination of different levels of managers, leads & teams. Technologies Used: • HTML5 • CSS3 • NPM • Bootstrap5 • JavaScript/jQuery • JSON • ES6/7 • AJAX • Figma/XD • SASS/LESS • SEOs • JSX • babel/webpack • ReactJs17 • Material UI • Mobix/Jotail • WCAG • SDLC

FLIPSPACES (E-COMM SECT) | FULL STACK ANGULAR DEVELOPER | Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

Its design tech project which brings discovery, design (select items & materials) & delivery (accordingly bill generation & contacting suppliers) experience under one roof for its customers and partners, where I converted incomplete build to polished product and managed it. Technologies Used: • MySQL • Angular4 • Bootstrap4 • Responsive UI • Cross Browser • GitHub • Node • AWS

C-DAC | STUDENT INTERN | Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Studied & applied Advanced Java concepts on the Bookworm Project (e-Library) where few ebooks were available to read freely & rests were available either to buy, rent, or lent. Implemented MySQL for storing backend data. Technologies Used: • HTML • CSS • Bootstrap4 • MySQL • Responsive UI • Cross Browser • GitHub • J2EE (Hibernate & Spring)

Soft Skills:

Excellent Communication | Team Player | Hard Worker | Multitasking | PositiveAttitude | Problem Solver | Flexibility

AWARDS

- Trophy in Socio-Techno-Culture Festival - IIT Jodhpur, 2015
- Trophy by Dept. of Physical Education - Banasthali University, 2015

MEMBER

- Gliding and Flying Club, 2019
- Student Pilot's License Holder, 2013-19
- Computer Society of India, 2015
- National Service Scheme (NSS), 2015

HOBBIES

- **Badminton**
- Healing & Meditation
- Listening Songs

CAREER COMPILER (EDU SECT) | FULL STACK JAVA INTERN | Jan 2018 - July 2018 Developed e-Cops application from scratch to extend online registration of reports, complaints,

FIRs, etc using ADVANCE J2EE TECHNOLOGY. Implemented backend by MySQL for storing data across JDBC drivers to perform CURD operations. Technologies Used: • HTML • CSS •

Bootstrap • MySQL • Responsive UI • Cross Browser • Git/GitHub • J2E • Apache Tomcat

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

- Manager, Graphics and Design Team Manager, Project Testers and Development Team and Managing Team.
- Head Coordinator of Registration team and coordinator in Promotion team (2017): N.S.C. (National Students' Convection) by BVICAM Delhi.
- Being Head Coordinator and Coordinator of college events: Organized various activities and special celebration events like National Students' Convection - NSC, Delhi Students' Convection, and Education Day etc.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified in React (Hooks, Router, Redux) / Maximilian Schwarzmuller / 18 Sept, 2022
- Usui Reiki Master / Lisa Powers and Natural Healer / 9 April, 2021
- PG Diploma in Advanced Computing/ C-DAC / Feb, 2019
- J2EE Hibernate with Spring Framework / Hewlett Packard Enterprise / 13 June, 2018
- Participated in INDIACom, 3rd International Conference / BVICAM / 16 Mar 18 Mar, 2016
- 7th Kyu Shotokan / World Karate and Asian Karate-Do Federation / 4 Mar, 2013
- Advanced Karmic Quotient Healer / Archana Gaur / 9 Feb, 2009